Andrew Hamlin

Software Engineering Leader Simsbury, CT 06070 | Phone (860) 810 - 6538 aahamlin@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin

Professional Summary

Engineering manager with 20+ years experience in development and delivery of distributed systems and applications. A servant leader who emphasizes communication, collaboration, ownership, and continuous improvement; and coaches XP practices, e.g., refactoring, pairing, TDD/BDD, and CI/CD. Successfully influenced and established lightweight processes in product team of 5 to 50+ persons, enabling effective forecasting, better risk mitigation, high-quality maintainable systems, consistent performance against OKRs, and satisfied customers.

Work Experience

Technical Co-Founder - Unplugg Enterprises, Easthampton, MA Apr 2019 - Dec 2019 Developed business plan, ran customer development studies, prototyped iOS & Android app with Dart, Flutter, Swift, Java, AWS AppSync (GraphQL/DynamoDB) and Adobe XD.

Senior Software Engineering Manager - Gerber Technology, Tolland, CT Apr 2018 - Dec 2019 Championed improvements to Agile SDLC incl. team-based design & estimation, code review, and Sprint planning that lowered bug rates 86% and increased throughput 70%. Managed 8 directs & 20 offshore contractors. On-boarded 25 via new hire, contract & acquisition.

Software Development Manager - Sailpoint Technologies, Austin, TX Dec 2016 - Mar 2018 Collaborated with peers and Product Managers to deliver cloud integrations, Angular UI, Java APIs, & SQL with 5 full-stack Scrum teams. Scripted ETL analysis of Jira project stats and dev metrics in Python. Established workflows with new localization partner and added 4 languages. Introduced security threat modeling to code design. Scrum master of 2 teams, totaling 16 dev & test engineers. Managed 8 directs. Led recruitment & on-boarding of 4 new hires.

Software Engineering Manager - Caradigm, Bellevue, WA / Remote Jul 2013 - Nov 2016 Led teams from planning to on-time delivery of two new products, as lead developer and scrum master. Envisioned, built and deployed TFS CI/CD pipeline enabling isolated polyglot build & test environments for full-stack applications including Javascript, C#/.NET, Java, Python, PowerShell, and SQL Server with automated testing and reporting capabilities.

Sustaining Engineering Manager - Caradigm, Bellevue, WA / Remote Jul 2012 - Jun 2013 Established Kanban process that delivered 50+ releases to production clinical healthcare environments and met 100% of our SLAs. Earned **2013 Caradigm Employee Recognition Award** for improving our customer satisfaction scores as measured by *KLAS Research*.

Software Development Engineer II - Microsoft Corporation, Andover, MA Jul 2010 - Jun 2012 Designed SOA and led incremental transition from Java to C#/.NET, PowerShell, & Hyper-V.

Principal Software Engineer - Sentillion, Andover, MA / Remote Dec 1999 - Jun 2010 Developed enterprise platform on Linux clusters in Java, Perl & OpenLDAP. Automated bare metal installation to ship initial 300 units on-time. Fixed LB algorithm eliminating downtime & support costs. Refactored HA solution to use OSS, saving \$1K/server in licensing fees.

Education

Daniel Webster College, Nashua, NH B.S., Management and Information Technology